sss.gov 2019-04-12

# Web Site Privacy Policy

### Website Privacy Policy

**SUBJECTS:**

  * Privacy Policy
  * What are Your Rights Under the Privacy Act of 1974?
  * Security Statement
  * Information Protection
  * Information that You Voluntarily Provide 
  * How Information is Used
  * Retention of Information
  * Cookies
  * Interaction with Children
  * Links to Other Sites
  * Accessability Statement
  * Freedom of Information Act (FOIA)
  * System of Records Notices
  * Computer Matching Program
  * Legal Citations
  * Senior Agency Official for Privacy (SAOP)
  * Privacy Impact Assessment Requests

* * *

#### **Privacy Policy**

Thank you for visiting the Selective Service System website. This service and its website is owned and operated by the Selective Service System and is committed to protecting the privacy of our visitors. We collect no personal information about you when you visit our website unless you choose to provide us with the information. Here is how we handle the information you provide during your visit to this website.

In addition to SSS’s official website on www.sss.gov, SSS uses social media and third-party (non-SSS) websites to share information and to engage with the general public.  Under those conditions, there may be third-party applications and/or services linked to or embedded on www.sss.gov to enhance functionality or facilitate website data analytics. Similarly, applications created by SSS may be embedded on third-party websites as a way to increase public awareness of Agency activities. The integration of these features is intended to provide a seamless user experience and enhance the publics ability to access information and interface with SSS.  Some third-party websites and applications may make personally identifiable information (PII) available to the public and/or SSS based on user controlled settings or the privacy policies of the third-party. SSS will not collect, (maintain, use, or share), PII that becomes available through SSS’s use of third-party websites or applications.

Please be aware that the privacy policy provided on social media and third-party websites that are not a part of the sss.gov domain may not be the same as the privacy policy described here. PII or other information you voluntarily share through social media, or a third-party website or application, may be accessible by non-government third parties. As described in these website policies, you can communicate directly with SSS without involving a third-party.  SSS will conduct and publish a Privacy Impact Assessment (PIA) for each use of a third-party website. Each use of a third-party website may have unique functionality or practices.

******back to top**

* * *

#### **What are Your Rights Under the Privacy Act of 1974?**

The Privacy Act of 1974 protects the personal information the federal government keeps on you in "systems of records (SOR)." SOR is information an agency controls that can be retrieved by name or some other personal identifier. The Privacy Act regulates how the government can disclose, share, provide access to, and maintain the personal information that it collects. Not all information collected online is covered by the Privacy Act.

The Act's major provisions require agencies to:

  * Publish a Privacy Act Notice in the Federal Register explaining the existence, character, and uses of a new or revised SOR;
  * Keep information about you accurate, relevant, timely, and complete to assure fairness in dealing with you; and
  * Allow you to, upon request, access and review your information held in a SOR.

An overview of the Privacy Act can be viewed at the following web site: <http://www.justice.gov/opcl/overview-privacy-act-1974-2012-edition>

The Selective Service Privacy Act statement can be viewed on the website below: Privacy Act Statement

**** **back to top**

* * *

#### **Security Statement**

If you browse through this website, read pages, or download information, we will gather and store certain information about your visit automatically. This information does not identify you personally and is only used to improve future visits to the site. The information we automatically collect and store is as follows:

  * The Internet domain (for example, "xcompany.com" if you use a private Internet access account or "yourschool.edu" if you connect from a university’s domain);
  * Your IP address (an IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you are surfing the Web) from which you access our website;
  * The type of browser and operating system used to access our site;
  * The date and time you access our site;
  * The pages you visit; and
  * If you linked to our website from another website, the address of that website.

We use this information to help us make our site more useful to visitors, to learn about the number of visitors to our site, and the types of technology our visitors use. We do not track or record information about individuals and their visits.

******back to top**

* * *

#### **Information Protection**

For site security purposes and to ensure that this service remains available to all users, this federal government computer system employs software programs to monitor network traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise cause damage. If such monitoring reveals evidence of possible abuse or criminal activity, such evidence may be provided to appropriate law enforcement officials. Unauthorized attempts to upload or change information on this server are strictly prohibited and may be punishable under the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986 and the National Information Infrastructure Protection Act or other law.

**** **back to top**

* * *

#### **Information that You Voluntarily Provide**

We do not collect personally identifiable information (PII) unless you choose to provide it to us. If you provide us with PII, for example, by sending an email or by filling out a form and submitting it through our website, we use that information to respond to your message and to help us provide you with the information and services that you request. All uses of that information are described on the webpage containing the form.

When you click the “Submit” button on any of the Web forms found on our sites, you are authorizing Selective Service to use the information submitted.

**** **back to top**

* * *

#### **How Information is Used**

The information we collect is used for a variety of purposes (e.g., to register you with Selective Service and to respond to requests for information. We make every effort to disclose clearly how information is used at the point where it is collected so you can determine whether you wish to provide the information.

**** **back to top**

* * *

#### **Retention of Information**

We destroy the information we collect when the purpose for which it was provided has been fulfilled unless we are required to keep it longer by statute or official policy. Electronically submitted information is maintained and destroyed according to the principles of the Federal Records Act and the regulations and records schedules approved by the National Archives and Records Administration. In some cases, information submitted to us may become an agency record and therefore might be subject to a Freedom of Information Act request.

Also, we are not responsible for the privacy practices employed by sites that may link to this website or of sites we link to (e.g., websites of professional organizations).

**** **back to top**

* * *

#### **Cookies**

"Cookies" are small bits of text that are either used for the duration of a session ("session cookies") or saved on a user’s hard drive in order to identify that user, or information about that user, the next time the user logs onto the website ("persistent cookies"). This website does not use persistent cookies or any other persistent tracking technology. Currently, we are using session cookies only. We do not retain any information collected by session cookies. Session cookies are automatically deleted at the end of a session; that is, when you close your browser.

**** **back to top**

* * *

#### **Interaction with Children**

Some websites offer educational content to children under age 13. This website does not. If a visitor under 13 uses this website, no personally identifiable information is collected from these visitors unless it is voluntarily submitted as a request for information or services. The information supplied is used to respond to the user’s inquiries or to provide services requested by the user.

**** **back to top**

* * *

#### **Links to Other Sites**

Our website contains links to various other federal agencies and private organizations. Once you link to another site, you are then subject to the privacy policies of the new site. It is always a good idea to read the Privacy Policy of any site you visit.

**** **back to top**

* * *

#### **Accessibility Statement**

We are committed to making this website accessible to all customers and staff in accordance with provisions of Section 508 of the Rehabilitation Act Amendments of 1998. If you have difficulty obtaining information from any page on this website, please contact us to get the material in another format. You should also, if possible, provide the URL of the page in this website referencing that information. In addition, if you have any Section 508-related questions, comments, or suggestions for improvement, please feel free to contact us:

By email: [Information@sss.gov](mailto:Information@sss.gov)

**** **back to top**

* * *

#### **Freedom of Information Act (FOIA)**

The Freedom of Information Act, enacted in 1966, provides that any person has a right, enforceable in court, of access to federal agency records, except to the extent that such records are protected from disclosure by one of nine exemptions or by one of three special law enforcement records exclusions.

For complete FOIA information, consult following website: FOIA Homepage.

**** **back to top**

* * *

#### 

#### **System of Records Notices**

  * [Integrated Mobilization Information Management System (IMIS) and Reserve and National Guard Personnel Records](https://www.federalregister.gov/documents/2017/06/30/2017-13768/privacy-act-system-of-records)

**** **back to top**

* * *

#### 

#### **Computer Matching Program**

  * [Computer Matching Program with the U.S. Department of Education](https://www.federalregister.gov/documents/2017/05/31/2017-11130/privacy-act-of-1974-computer-matching-program)

**** **back to top**

* * *

#### 

#### **Legal Citations**

  * [Code of Federal Regulations, SSS Privacy Act Regulations (32 CFR 1665)](https://www.gpo.gov/fdsys/pkg/CFR-2017-title32-vol6/xml/CFR-2017-title32-vol6-part1665.xml)

**** **back to top**

* * *

#### 

#### **Senior Agency Official for Privacy (SAOP)**

If you wish to speak with the Senior Agency Official for Privacy (SAOP) send an email to [information@sss.gov](mailto:information@sss.gov?subject=Senior%20Agency%20Official%20for%20Privacy).

**** **back to top**

* * *

#### **Privacy Impact Assessment Requests**

To request a copy of our IT systems’ privacy impact assessments, please contact [privacyassessment@sss.gov](mailto:privacyassessment@sss.gov). The Agency’s IT staff will assist you with this request.

  * Privacy Impact Assessment for the Selective Service System
  * Privacy Impact Assessment for the Registration, Compliance and Verification (RCV) System
  * Privacy Impact Assessment for the Information Management Information System (IMIS)

******back to top**
